Guide to the Paul Venable Turner Papers SC0948
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Paul Venable Turner papers
1969-2016
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Turner, Paul Venable
SC0948
13.5 Linear Feet
Papers consist of research materials (including photocopies of original documents), correspondence, drafts of articles, photograpic illustrations, and finished publications on architects Joseph Jacques Ramée and Le Corbusier.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Paul V. Turner, trained as an architect and art historian, has been on the faculty of Stanford's Dept. of Art and Art History since 1971. His publications include THE EDUCATION OF LE CORBUSIER; JOSEPH RAMÉE: INTERNATIONAL ARCHITECT OF THE REVOLUTIONARY ERA; THE FOUNDERS & THE ARCHITECTS: THE DESIGN OF STANFORD UNIVERSITY; and CAMPUS: AN AMERICAN PLANNING TRADITION. He chaired the university committee overseeing the repair of Frank Lloyd Wright's Hanna House, badly damaged in the 1989 Loma Prieta earthquake, and in 2001 received the Lloyd W. Dinkelspiel Award for distinctive contributions to undergraduate education.
Description of the Collection
Papers consist of research materials (including photocopies of original documents), correspondence, drafts of articles, photograpic illustrations, and finished publications on architects Joseph Jacques Ramée and Le Corbusier.
Architects -- France.; Architects -- France.; Le Corbusier; Turner, Paul Venable; Turner, Paul Venable; Le Corbusier; Ramée, Joseph Jacques; Turner, Paul Venable; Turner, Paul Venable; Ramée, Joseph Jacques; Turner, Paul Venable
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2009-126
  - Papers pertaining to Joseph Ramée
    - Ramée's Basic Information
      - Documents on Ramée's life (see also files of Bléraucourt documents, etc.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Chronologies (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Articles and references to Ramée (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ramée's Publications
      - Jardins Irréguliers (1823) (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Recueil de Cottages (1837) (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Parcs et Jardins (ca. 1839) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - PVT's Publications and Lectures on Ramée
      - Joseph Ramée, International Architect of the Revolutionary Era (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - "Joseph-Jacques Ramée's First Career," June 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - "David Parish's Country House Reconstructed," October 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - "Joseph Ramée's Design for Baltimore, 1813: A New Type of Urban Monument in America," 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Ramée article for M. Racine, "Créateurs de Jardins et de paysages en France..," 2001 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Article in Joseph Ramée, Gartenkunst, Architektur und Dekoration, Hamburg, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - "Searching for Ramée," Union College, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Encyclopedia articles (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Baker lecture, Union College, Oct. 1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - S.A.H. Annual Meeting, New Haven, April 1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Stanford Art Department talk, May 1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Oxford University talk, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Talk on Ramée in Paris, 9 March 1990, and Charleville, 3 March 1990, with related correspondence (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Society of Architectural Historians talk, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - PVT's Cambridge University Press Book
      - Ramée: Cambridge Univ. Press (memorandum of agreement) 1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Ramée: reproduction permissions (1) (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Ramée: reproduction permissions (2) (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Ramée: reproduction permissions (3) (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Reviews of book (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Topical Aspects of Ramée's Work
      - Examples of Ramée's handwriting (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Drawings by Ramée (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Search for Ramée's lost drawings (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Ramée's decorative reliefs and other interior docoration (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - "Guimard Motif" and triumphal arches (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Wm Beckford and Oriental tents (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Architectural materials (stucco, etc.) (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Vignole (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Europe after 1816 – miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Cottages (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Ice houses (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Log cabins (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - France
      - Ramée documents at Musée de Blérancourt (see also correspondence with Blérancourt) (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence with Musée de Blérancourt 1985-1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Didier Coupaye – correspondence and documents 1987-1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence with J. Plault and documents found by him, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - M. Georget la Chesnais – correspondence and documents, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Givet, Charlemont and Massembre: correspondence and documents pertaining to (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Early work in France (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Belanger and Cellerier (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Perregaux House (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Berthault – Récamier House (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - "Comble de forme circulaire" (DeLorme system, Bohlendächer, etc.) (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Fête de la Féderation, 1790 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Ramée's Loterie design - 1911 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Viller-Agron (correspondence with M. de Lavaulx) (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Mont-Dieu, Carlepont, Flize, Verneuil, etc. (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Place Louis XVI design, 1829 (Paris) (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Germany
      - Ramée – Saxony (Thuringia) (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Erfurt (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Gotha (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Meiningen (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Weimar (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Hamburg and Elbehaussee – miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Plageberg and correspondence with Ingrid Schubert (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Mecklenburg - Schwerin (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Ludwigslust Mausoleum and Mecklenburg correspondence (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Ramée – Mecklenburg correspondence (from Staatsarchiv Schwerin) (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Germany (Hamburg) 1830s (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Hirschfeld and garden design (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Belgium and Denmark
      - Belgium - miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Denmark (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - United States
      - Documents from New York Historical Society, etc. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Documents from O. D. Young Library, St. Lawrence University (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Northern New York State: articles, maps, etc. (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence between Ramée, Parish, et. al. (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - David Parish – articles, documents, etc. (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Parish Country house (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Parishville, New York (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Ogdensburg, New York (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Rossie, New York (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Waddington, New York (& Ogden Island) (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Antwerp, New York: St. Michael's Church (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Duane House, Duanesburg, New York (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - New York State: buildings possibly by Ramée (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence with Roger Kennedy and a review of his book (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence with Claire Bonney, 1985-1997 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Northern New York State – miscellaneous correspondence, 1985-1992 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Van Rensselaer (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Stoves ("Russian," etc.) (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Philadelphia (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Baltimore (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Washington Monument, Baltimore (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - 1814 Pennsylvania Academy Exhibition (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Ramée's wallpaper designs (& Schumacher reproductions) (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Ramée's wallpapers: "double column" pattern (Schumacher reproduction) (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Ramée's wallpapers: "gilded ironwork" pattern (Schumacher reproduction) (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Other Schumacher reproductions of Ramée's wallpapers (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Daniel Ramée
      - D. Ramée – bibliography, etc. (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous publications relevant to D. Ramée (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - D. Ramée – miscellaneous materials (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - D. Ramée: Le Moyen Age Monumental…, 1843 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - D. Ramée: Manuel de L'Histoire…, 1843 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Le Doux's L'Architecture… and D. Ramée's edition of it, 1847 (also: Polyphilos) (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - D. Ramée: Théologie Cosmogonique (1853) (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - D. Ramée: Histoire Générale de l'Architecture…(1860) (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - D. Ramée: Action de Jésus… (1864) (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - D. Ramée: Le Congres de Vienne…, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - D. Ramée: Dictionnaire…de l'Architecture, 1868 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - D. Ramée: La République…, 1872 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - D. Ramée: Les Noces Vermeilles…Saint-Barthélemi, 1897 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - D. Ramée: L'Architecture et la Construction Pratiques, 1885 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - D. Ramée: other publications (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Photographs
      - Ramée: figures 1-29 (complete) (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Ramée: figures 30-59 [see oversize box for figure 41] (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Ramée: figures 60-106 [see oversize box for figure 60] (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Ramée: figures 107-144 [see oversize box for figures 129, 141] (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Ramée: figures 145-186 [figures 150, 151 were returned to Mecklenburg correspondence, box 5] (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Ramée: figures 219-262 [see oversize box for figures 237, 253-257, 259-262] (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Ramée: figures 263-300 [see oversize box for figures 265, 282] (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Ramée: color prints of watercolors (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Drawings by P. V. Turner, reproduced in Ramée book (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Ramée: France (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Blérancourt Museum documents (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Ramée: Belgium (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Ramée: Denmark (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Ramée: Germany (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Ramée: United States (except Union College) (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Ramée's wallpapers (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Ramée's publications (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Daniel Ramée (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Photographs (contact sheets, etc.) (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Transparencies from P. Povlsen of Erichsen House, Copenhagen, 1993 (Box 11)
      - Microfilm of David Parish letter books in the New York Historical Society (Box 11)
      - Assorted photocopies of illustrations (Box 12)
      - Figures 41, 60, 129, 141 (Box 12 os)
      - Figures 187, 200, 237 (Box 12 os)
      - Figures 253-257, 259-262 (Box 12 os)
      - Figures 265, 282 (Box 12 os)
      - Jardins Irréguliers: photos of illustrations from (Box 12 os)
      - Union College: Klein engraving (Box 12 os)
  - Papers pertaining to Le Corbusier
    - Note cards made while researching the dissertation, mainly at the Fondation Le Corbusier in 1969-70 (Box 13)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Photocopied documents from the Fondation Le Corbusier (also includes typescript: "Nous Sommes le 7 février 1970…Albert Jeanneret nous parle de son frère Le Corbusier") (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Jeanneret's signatures (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Catalogue of Le Corbusier's library (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Chronology of Jeanneret's book acquisition (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Provensal, L'Art de demain (photocopy) (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Photocopies of miscellaneous items in Le Corbusier's library (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - The Education of Le Corbusier (unbound copy of the dissertation) (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Garland Publishing Co. edition of L-C book, correspondence and other materials, 1976-87 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Education of L-C: reviews, etc. (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - French edition of the book: correspondence and other material, 1985-1995 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Manuscript as revised for French edition (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - PVT: articles on Le Corbusier (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Lecture on L-C and Frank Lloyd Wright, at MIT, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - "Frank Lloyd Wright and the Young Le Corbusier" with related correspondence (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - F.L. Wright and Le Corbusier article: Follow-up (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Le Corbusier: miscellaneous correspondence (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Photographic prints used for illustrations in the original dissertation (some used in Garland edition) (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Photographs (extras) (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Photographs (negatives and contact sheets) (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Photographs (returned to PVT by Jean Clay, source unknown) (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Photographs (from Fondation L-C, stamped on back) (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Photographs (duplicates and photos not in French edition) (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Photographs ("stats" used by Garland) (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Photographs for "Frank Lloyd Wright and the Young Le Corbusier" (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Photographs for "Frank Lloyd Wright and the Young Le Corbusier" (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Photographs for "Frank Lloyd Wright and the Young Le Corbusier" (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Catalogue de la bibliothèque de Le Corbusier avant 1930, La Fondation Le Corbusier, Paris, février 1970. (Box 18)
    - The Education of Le Corbusier: A Study of the Development of Le Corbusier's Thought, 1900-1920, Ph.D. thesis, Harvard University, April 1971. (Box 18)
    - The Education of Le Corbusier, Garland Publishing, Inc., New York and London, 1977. (Box 18)
    - La Formation de Le Corbusier: Idéalisme et mouvement moderne, Éditions Macula, Paris, 1987. (Box 18)
    - La Formazione di Le Corbusier: Idealismo e Movimento moderno, Jaca Book, Milano, 2001. (Box 18)
- Audiovisual Material, Accession ARCH_2018_056
  - American Architecture Urbanism (Art 176)
    - American Architecture Urbanism: Slide Review 1, 1998 Mar 10; 1_01; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
    - American Architecture Urbanism: Slide Review 2, 1998 Mar 12; 1_02; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
    - American Architecture Urbanism: Lecture 3, 1998 Jan 13; 1_03; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
    - American Architecture Urbanism: Lecture 4, 1998 Jan 15; 1_04; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
    - American Architecture Urbanism: Lecture 5, 1998 Jan 20; 1_05; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
    - American Architecture Urbanism: Lecture 6, 1998 Jan 22; 1_06; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
    - American Architecture Urbanism: Lecture 7, 1998 Jan 27; 1_07; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
    - American Architecture Urbanism: Lecture 8 (Technology), 1998 Jan 29; 1_08; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
    - American Architecture Urbanism: Lecture 9 (Olmsted Richardson), 1998 Feb 7; 1_09; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
    - American Architecture Urbanism: Lecture 10, 1998 Feb 12; 1_10; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
    - American Architecture Urbanism: Lecture 11, 1998 Feb 17; 1_11; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
    - American Architecture Urbanism: Lecture 12 (Frank Lloyd Wright), 1998 Feb 19; 1_12; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
    - American Architecture Urbanism: Lecture 13, 1998 Feb 24; 1_13; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
    - American Architecture Urbanism: Lecture 14, 1998 Feb 26; 1_14; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
    - American Architecture Urbanism: Lecture 15, 1998 Mar 3; 1_15; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
    - American Architecture Urbanism: Lecture 16, 1998 Mar 5; 1_16; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - Paul Turner - Hanna House Interview, 1999 Jun 23; 1_17; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - "Mrs. Hoover's Pueblo Walls", 1999 May 4
    Scope and Contents
    Talk on the Lou Henry Hoover House. Public lecture, Annenberg Auditorium.
    - "Mrs. Hoover's Pueblo Walls", 1999 May 4; 1_18; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
    - "Mrs. Hoover's Pueblo Walls", 1999 May 4; 1_19; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - "Frank Lloyd Wright the San Francisco Bay Area", 2016 Nov 3; 1_20; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
    Keynote address at annual conference of the Frank Lloyd Wright Building Conservancy, San Francisco.
  - Talk on the architect Joseph Ramée, 2007 Oct 24; 1_21; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
    At Union College, Schenectady, New York.
  - Talk on modern American architecture, 2013 Sep 17; 1_22; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
    At symposium at Marin County Civic Center.
  - Talk on the American campus, at University in Madrid, Spain, 2012 Sep 21; 1_23; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - "Stanford's Damaged Treasure: Frank Lloyd Wright's Hanna House", 1996 Feb 29
    Public lecture, Annenberg Auditorium
    - "Stanford's Damaged Treasure: Frank Lloyd Wright's Hanna House", 1996 Feb 29; 1_24; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
    - "Stanford's Damaged Treasure: Frank Lloyd Wright's Hanna House", 1996 Feb 29; 1_25; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2018-073
  - The Lou Henry Hoover House
    Material relating to the research and publication of the book Mrs. Hoover's Pueblo Walls: The Primitive and the Modern in the Lou Henry Hoover House [Stanford: Stanford University Press, 2004].
    - Preliminary, unbound copy of the book. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and notes by Turner. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Photographs used in the book, and reproduction permissions. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Articles on the Hoover House. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Photographs from the Hoover Institution Archives (HIA). (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Documents from the Stanford University Archives (SUA). (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence and notes regarding material in the Herbert Hoover Presidential Library (HHPL). (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Documents from the HHPL. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Hoover Scrapbooks at the HHPL. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence by Lou Henry Hoover (LHH) regarding the house. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Birge Clark's "Memoirs" regarding the house. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous material regarding the house. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous photographs. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - General information on the Hoovers. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Turner's correspondence with members of the Hoover family. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - LHH's interest in American Indian art. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - LHH and Mary Austin. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Charles Whittlesey's architecture (and Lynn Horiuchi's research on Whittlesey). (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - President Mrs. David Starr Jordan's visit to New Mexico with Charles Lummis, 1898. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - LHH and Hoover Tower (information from Jeffrey Tilman). (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - LHH's faculty cottages at Stanford. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Early interest in the Pueblos. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Pueblo Revival architecture. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Irving Gill's architecture. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Turner's talk on the Hoover House, 1999. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Students' course papers on the Hoover House. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Campus: An American Planning Tradition
    Material relating to the research and publication of the book Campus: An American Planning Tradition [New York & Cambridge, MA: Architectural History Foundation & MIT Press, 1984].
    - Book contract and related correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Hitchcock Award (information relating to the book's winning of the Society of Architectural Historians' Hitchcock Award, for the best book on architectural history published in 1984). (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Selected reviews of the book. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Reproduction permissions for the illustrations in the book. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Digital version of the book (reproduction permissions and other information about the digital version of the book created on the Stanford Library's website, 2008). (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Photographs used for the book's illustrations (arranged in the order of the figure numbers). (Box 2, Folder 6-13)
    - Additional photographs of university and college architecture and campus plans (English colleges, and American schools and campuses, arranged by period). (Box 2, Folder 14-19)
  - The Ruth Lucie Stern Research Building of the Stanford Medical School
    Material relating to the research and publication of the article "Stanford's Unknown Architectural Milestone: The Ruth Lucie Stern Research Building, by Architects Birge and David Clark" [Sandstone & Tile, vol. 35, number 3, Fall 2011, pp 14-23].
    - Copies of the article. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Architectural plans of the Stern Building. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Articles and other information on the Stern Building. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - "Historic Resource Evaluation Report" on the Stern Building and other buildings at California Pacific Medical Center. (Box 2, Folder 23)